

Experienced UI/UX leader with 20+ years in enterprise platforms, design systems, and digital ecosystems. My full-stack software engineering background paired with design skills provide a unique blend of abilities that allow me to drive innovation and execute on creative solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Medtronic
2019 - PRESENT

SENIOR PRINCIPAL UI/UX DESIGN LEAD

- Led the design and development of the global Medtronic Design System by partnering with brand and bringing together a group of cross-functional UX practitioners across Medtronic. Create and manage Sketch and Figma component libraries and design documentation. Act as PO for the Angular development kit that implements the design system.
- Supported the development of an AR/VR design system.
- Oversaw UI/UX for the CareLink cardiac patient monitoring platform, driving design, vision, strategy, and architecture. Partner with PMs and POs to define product and project roadmaps. Design primary workflow experiences, overall UI look and feel, common interaction patterns, and information architecture for CareLink. Perform user research and testing to identify core user problems and validate our designs.
- Defined design-driven software development processes and success metrics for efficient product delivery.
- Contributed to the growth of the Human Factors and User Experience team from <10 to 30+ members
- Provide in-house design services such as icons, logos, graphics, animations, slide templates, video production.

Veritas Technologies

2017-2019

SENIOR PRINCIPAL UI/UX DESIGN ENGINEER

- Led the UX design of a brand new web UI for the flagship enterprise data protection product, NetBackup. Re-imagined workflows to adapt to modern user needs. Engaged with customers throughout design cycle to understand user problems, ideate on solutions, and validate designs.
- Championed new processes and culture changes to accommodate a new design led paradigm within the organization.
- Led the design and implementation of the Veritas Design language to bring standards across multiple products within the company.
- Led a global team of designers to support 18 engineering scrum teams.

Symantec Corp/Veritas Technologies

2002-2017

PRINCIPAL FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Solo designed and developed a dashboard app that allows engineers to create their own custom dashboards to display metrics that are pertinent to their job.
 Developed over 100 customizable widgets displaying data through charts, tables, and some highly specialized views.
- Designed, developed, and maintained multiple full stack web applications to support engineering operations, leveraging technologies like Django, Angular, Ruby, PostgreSQL, and more.

CONTACT





in in/david-y-wan

EDUCATION

BS Computer Engineering, U of MN Twin Cities

TOOLS & SKILLS

Figma, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom, Axure

Javascript/Typescript, HTML/CSS, Python, Java, PHP, Ruby, SQL, NoSQL, Angular, React, cloud technologies

ACHIEVEMENTS

2 design patents

Three-time Medtronic Human-centered Design Awards finalist

Two-time PCS Hackathon best-in-show winner

Four-time PCS Hackathon category winner

Three-time Veritas Hackathon winner